Hello there!
It's so hot!
I'm gonna burn to death!
I don't see any of us dying from these
temps, but I hope I don't overheat.
We'll be okay, right?
This is all because of that sheer pervert?
It's true.
Heavy's letter is the reason
we're here in the first place.
We came here to track him down.
I must leave you and go see to a
personal matter, but fear not comrades!
I shall rejoin you as soon as
my errand is taken care of.
P .S.
Take care of yourselves and of
course your footwear This letter
must mean that he's headed for
the Scorching Sand Stratum,
doesn't it?
Probably based on how he acted yesterday
Then it would be best if we followed him,
right?
I personally don't care at
all that much about Heavy,
but I'd like to check up on
the Scorching Sand Stratum.
So it's fine by me if we go!
So, there you have it.
And here we are in the
scorching sand stratum.
Now I'd better do something before
everyone melts in this intense heat.
I'll turn on my temperature
regulation feature.
Oh, things just cool
down a lot. Thanks, Boxo.
I know, fair Lamas, I want some cool too.
This cold is just what the Boxo
ordered. Yeah, right? I know.
I'll wear that cloak Boxo got
me in the dark forest stratum.
Not that she should need to use
another heat countermeasure,
but Llamas is being nice and making it
a point to wear the cloak I gave her.
So, Boxo, how do I look?
Ad or a bo-oh.
Aw, thank you.
It pays to compliment her when
she responds so, well, adorably.
But it's no time for
soothing our discomfort.
We need to go to the Hunters Association
and deliver the letter from Director Bear.
On the outside, I'm just a big metal box,
But inside I've still got a human soul!
In this new world of
wonders I travel to and
fro on the back of my
super strong partner Lamas!
The name's Boxxo! Hello there!
That means yes, by the way!
This is a dream of a dream.
I'm done with you, I'll
be able to splash it.
I'll be there again.
It's a dream, it's a dream.
It's a dream.
We're here from the
Clearflow Lake Stratum.
We have a letter from the director there,
and we'd like to deliver it to
Director Scorching if we could.
My word, Master Boxo, it can't be!
I haven't seen you in so long.
My sincerest apologies if I worried you.
Hello there.
Oh, Mishuel.
I did sort of forget
about him, to be honest.
Oops, my bad.
Well, anyway, now I've caught up
with everyone who got scattered.
I got sent to this place by myself,
and as I was pondering how
I had no way to get back,
I ended up helping defend the village
when a swarm of monsters attacked.
I'm glad that you're okay.
Don't worry, everyone else is safe
back in the Clear Flow Lake stratum.
Oh, I'm relieved to hear it.
I'm glad we ran into Mishuel.
I wonder how he's been faring
on his own in this stratum.
Here's hoping his communication
issues have improved a bit.
It's such a relief you're here, Master.
All the stress and tension these past
few days have really wrecked my stomach.
Wrecked it!
It did nothing for your looks, either.
I guess there's no way you were
going to improve that quickly.
Thank you for waiting.
The director says he will see you now.
Welcome, friends.
I'm glad you can make it.
Although this stratum has had
its own fair share of weirdness,
what with the monster swarm
attacking the village and all,
we fought them all off, caught what
appeared to be their commander?
and threw their butts in jail.
Wow, that's impressive.
So, um, we have a letter here
for you from Director Bear.
Huh.
I see that you guys have
had it pretty rough as well.
What?
You can provide us with water? Yes.
That would be a big help!
This heat has the Oasis low on
water and things are looking bad.
Can I ask for it right away? Hello there!
Since I started doing business on
this stratum with its horrible heat,
the cold drinks have been flying
off the proverbial shelves.
Been selling with no breaks from dawn
till dusk every day without fail.
Busy day, huh, Boxo? Yes.
What should we do after this?
Shoei's gone off somewhere.
Ooh,
do you maybe want to go check out the magic
item shop that was selling those boots?
Good idea.
Some sightseeing at night could be nice.
Hello there.
I wonder what kind of magic item this is.
Ah,
that one allows you to
clean your bath water
and store it in a bucket
so you can use it again.
Looks like Llamas is
going to do some shopping
before hitting up the
merchant for information.
Wow, that would really come in handy.
I'd like to buy it, please.
Oh, thank you for your business, miss.
I've really been in luck lately.
You're the third new customer
who's coming today alone.
Would the others be a man
dressed like a clergyman
and a short-haired woman
with a bow on her back?
Oh, um, yes, as a matter of fact.
Why?
Do you know them, miss?
What did they have to say?
Well, the clergyman had questions.
He asked where I'd gotten some boots
I sold recently, then he left, but...
That information is confidential.
That was heavy, no doubt about it.
Oh, sure, but would you mind telling me
which hunter sold you those boots, please?
I'm sorry, I have to
think of my reputation.
Looks like disclosure of personal info
is problematic even in this other world.
In that case... Letter! Uh, what? Letter?
Oh, you mean those letters.
That's right.
I've got letters of introduction from the
director here and one from Suori, too.
Hmm. Let's see.
This one's from Director
Scorching and what?
One from that giant corporation, too?
Suori's letter had an even bigger
effect than Director Scorching's?
That's wild.
Suori calling herself
the daughter of a big
-time merchant might be an understatement.
I'll make an exception
and tell you this time.
There's no surviving in this business
if you cross those two, you know.
The salesman is scared out of her wits.
I'm very curious to know
what was in that letter.
The one who sold the
boots to me was Tashtay,
a hunter who's pretty
active on the stratum.
Mr.
Boxo, why couldn't you have invited me to
join you on your evening stroll tonight?
When I dine alone, women always end up
approaching me and it stresses me out!
The fun thing about Mishuel
is that he's being sincere.
I am being sarcastic, though.
Well, in any case, I asked Director
Scorching about this hunter called Tashtay.
Apparently, he's the leader of a hunter
team known as the Billowing Flames.
They number around a dozen in total.
I was told they're
currently exploring some
ruins in a desert region of this stratum.
Hello there!
If you wish to parlay with this Tashtay,
then it seems your only option
is to make for the ruins.
But going there would mean having to
cross that awful desert, wouldn't it?
Hello there!
I thought so.
Oh, Master Boxo, would you mind
terribly if I accompanied you, please?
I wish he wouldn't look at
me like an abandoned puppy.
I need to handle this skillfully.
And that's for you, Apprentice.
Master Boxo called me his apprentice!
Anything, you name it!
Hold on!
Are you planning to disappear again?
Why are you trying to deal
with this all by yourself?
We have our issues, but
we're all on the same side.
This is a personal matter.
I simply don't wish to
inconvenience everyone.
There you go, deciding on your own!
Without even discussing it!
Like Captain Carry Oil.
Now you're doing what he did.
Maybe I'm just not trustworthy.
He didn't talk to me.
But if he had been honest,
maybe these could have turned out
differently and we'd all be together.
Aw, Shui.
So you all came here
in search of me, then.
I am deeply sorry to have
caused you such trouble.
If you think you've caused trouble,
then I want you to talk it out.
That's right.
You leaving without saying
anything is what made us worry.
Yes, yes.
I think I understand.
I doubt you'll like this story, but
are you willing to hear it? Mm-hmm.
It happened back before I
joined the Menagerie of Fools.
A childhood friend and I
were working as hunters.
We knew each other well and
made an incredible team.
People were lauding us as
the next up-and-coming duo.
So Heavy had a partner before.
One day,
after a series of lucky breaks,
I received a surprisingly
hefty reward and I decided to
get my friend some new boots
for her upcoming birthday.
Those boots were the untiring God's feet.
The boots I won were the
same ones you gave her?
Yes, that's right.
She, my friend, was pleased with them too.
She wore those boots everywhere
she went without fail.
She would always say she'd never
give them up no matter what,
and she said it with a smile every time.
Heavy's expression speaks volumes.
There's no question how
important his friend was to him.
Not long after,
we were attacked by bandits while
on assignment escorting a merchant,
and a blow from an adversary
left me unconscious.
Once I came to, I was greeted by the
horrible sight of corpses all around me.
There before my eyes were my friend's
remains, her legs cut off at the knees,
Hewn off crudely, cruelly With
an axe or other rough blade
My heart broke She had tied them
too tightly because they meant
so much to her And the bandits
couldn't get them off of her
They wore masks so I
don't know their faces
My only clue was that
pair of boots they stole
And so,
clinging to hope I became
obsessed with footwear
Single-minded in my
quest for vengeance That
brings us to now I never
expected Heavy to have
such a tragic hero past
I may be a clergyman,
but my heart has been full of
naught but revenge ever since.
It's pathetic when you
consider the judgment I
doled out to Captain
Kerioyl and his family.
You idiots!
Both you and the captain,
you're total dumbasses!
If you had talked about it,
we might have found the boots and
the people who sold them much sooner!
If you had shared your own sad story,
they might have been willing to talk about
their family problems and
we'd still be together!
Yes, but this is my personal
business - Don't you yes-butt me!
Can't you see things turned out this way
because everyone's so full of secrets?
I'm sick of the lies and deception.
It's really this simple.
If you want help, all you have to do is
explain the situation and ask for help.
If it's too much or I don't
want to do it, I'll say.
If what you're doing is wrong, as a
comrade, I'll do all I can to stop you.
So I wish you'd stop deciding and be a
burden or that you already know my answer.
It's infuriating.
You're right. I was wrong.
My fear made everything much worse.
Thank you so much, Shui.
I'm grateful.
Don't sweat it.
I'm just glad that you get it.
Everyone, might I request your assistance?
The answer is obvious.
Mm-hmm.
I've got your back, friend.
At your service. Oh, fine.
I'll help if you insist.
Hello there.
Huh?
Alright.
Our first obstacle is finding a
way through the scorching desert.
The environment is so harsh that even
walking through it will be difficult.
I wonder if that magic
item shop has anything
that could maybe help
us deal with the heat.
Sounds like you're in a bind.
When did you get here, Hulemy?
Just now.
I haven't had time to unpack.
We wanted to come along, too!
Are you going to be okay in this heat?
I may be a snow fairy, but I'm not
going to melt if it gets too hot.
Besides, I can cool down
the air if I need to.
As for the temperature problem,
I have a solution for that.
This magic item has the effect of
blocking heat and cooling nearby moisture.
It'll turn any sweat and
humidity into a refreshing mist.
Simply incredible.
With that item, I bet we'd be able
to cross the desert with ease.
Also, these are for Llamas.
They're from the Dark
Forest Stratum Weapons Shop.
Apparently, they can
somehow change their weight.
Amazing!
Those will make her attacks
way stronger and help
her maintain control when
she's going full tilt.
All right, I'm not as worried anymore.
I seem to have caused
quite the kerfuffle. Yes!
Truth be told, I never
planned on telling anyone.
But I suppose I ought to think, Shui...
It can't have been easy,
but at least now he's able to unload some
of the burdens he's had to carry alone.
I'm not naive enough to
think that everything
will be resolved during this one outing,
but maybe I'll find a stopping point.
I hope it works out.
So do I.
It's as hot as we expected.
No, even hotter, I'd say.
Even though we're wearing the
cloaks Hulemy made for us,
it seems to be tough going for everyone.
We'll scratch that, not everyone.
Just a little farther, guys,
then we'll take a break.
Llamas and Botan are doing fine.
Thanks to my temperature regulation
powers, Llamas isn't sweating at all.
And Botan seems dandy with all
the cold air Kiko is providing.
You're so cold.
If you could be my boyfriend for
just this stratum, that'd be amazing.
I'd even say for being best friends.
Come now, you two.
He's my master.
Boxo is looking more and more attractive.
Honestly, you could just
have me at this point.
Oh, master, I'd do anything you ask me.
Now that I look close, his
body is like a pair of boots.
Snap out of it.
The more you three talk,
the less sense you make.
Ah, this is happening.
I feel alive again.
Leave it to Master Boxo.
I didn't expect the heat to
be too much for the clothes.
It's not like they were useless.
When I took mine off, it was so hot,
I thought I was going to
shrivel up and die right there.
Hmm?
Is that some sort of calendar
they use in this world?
Calendar?
What was that?
Did you say something, Boxo?
Is that a calendar?
Those numbers are dates, aren't they?
Yeah, that's exactly it.
Since we had a moment, I
wanted to check today's date.
Hmm.
Oh, one of the dates is circled in red.
Uh-huh.
It marks a certain anniversary.
Got it.
I'll leave it at that.
I shouldn't pry into her private affairs.
Whoa that's the desert pillar.
Yep the desert pillar is supposed to
be huge so it's likely still far off.
Desert pillar is apparently another
name for the ruins of an old tower.
It's said to be a hundred
stories tall and the
stratum lord can be found
on the very top floor.
His black feathers look striking
against the cloudless sky.
Wait what? Kuroyata!
They say you saw him disappear, too.
Yeah, he vanished into thin air.
Good to know I wasn't just seeing things.
I don't see anything.
I was sure this was the spot, though.
Wait, something seems
kind of weird here. Huh?
Whoa, Lamas. What's going on?
The tower's really close.
It's right there in front of us.
Huh?
Why are you looking at me like that?
I never would have guessed the
desert pillar would be this close.
It looks like there's some kind of illusion
magic at work, similar to my blessing.
That makes sense, Kuroyata disappeared
after flying past that point.
Which was making us misjudge the distance.
I'm betting this trick was set up on purpose,
to keep anyone from getting too close.
Kuroyata!
Thank goodness
Yes.
Let's see.
He said there were a bunch of
what seemed to be lookouts,
but they went inside to get
arrows when they spotted him,
so this would be a good time to go in.
We can't afford to pass up this
chance that Kuroyata set up for us.
One and two!
It's cold in here.
Monster!
It's enormous!
But something's wrong.
Why aren't they reacting?
They look like they're
waiting for instructions
but the commander here
has already been captured.
That makes sense it lines
up with what director
scorching told us maybe
the commander is a fake.
To make us lower our
guard while they build up
their forces and make plans
to attack the village.
That would certainly
explain this situation wait
a sec i just thought of a
way to turn this around.
On him here goes nothing
nice
the
plan's working heavy's using his
illusions to make These monsters
think that their buddies are us.
Time to take this new
gear out on a test run.
Let's start by getting heavier.
I did it!
That was surprisingly effective.
It looks like Field will be able
to save up quite a bit of power.
That was the easy part.
Now we've got to deal with any
ambushes or traps waiting ahead.
Voxo, do you think you could go in front?
Your barrier is probably
going to come in handy here.
Yes, yes.
I'll be right there with you. Hey, sorry.
I don't mean to interrupt
while you're making plans.
But do you think I could have seconds?
I've still got a back-ish.
Voxo, be ready for anything
from this point forward.
Hello there.
Let's go.
All right, we made it!
Everyone, you can come up now!
Is something the matter, Hulemy?
I was just thinking that if whoever set
these traps knew what we were doing to them,
they'd be pretty mad.
For sure.
If it were me, I don't
know if I could handle it.
It appears there are enemies
waiting beyond the door.
Right.
Llamas, go ahead and
bust it wide open. Yeah!
Knock, knock!
Looks like they were
lurking behind the door
so they could pounce on
us the second it opened.
They definitely weren't expecting that.
They must be the Billowing Flames.
Who the hell do you guys
think you are? That man.
He matches the description
we were given for Tashtay.
It's him.
There's no doubt about it.
We're a group of hunters who came
here from the Clearflow Lake Stratum.
So, you're from another stratum.
What are you doing here?
If you must know, the reason we came is to
discuss some important business with you.
But we received more of a
welcome than we expected.
You want to talk business?
You're going to tell us how
the hell you found out that we
were hiding monsters in here
so we could attack the village?
Sure enough, that was
their plan all along.
First, I'd appreciate it if you
cleared something up for me.
Huh?
Your group has been conspiring
with the Netherlord.
And that's the reason why you've been able
to control the monsters
on the first floor.
Does that just about sum everything up?
If you already know that much,
then I suppose there's no
point in trying to play dumb.
Yeah, it's only temporary, but
we're working with the Netherlord.
But why are you on the Demon Lord's side?
You're only hurting innocent people!
Yeah, yeah.
You could spare me all
that goody-two-shoes talk.
We're doing it for money, of course.
It's a no-brainer when we're getting enough
money that we never have to work again.
From the way you're talking,
it sounds as if you're quite comfortable
with doing illegal
things for personal gain.
Got a problem with that?
Robberies, rapes, and even murder.
It all blends together after a while.
What do you expect from a former bandit?
Believe me,
there's nothing that feels
better than trampling
over a weakling while they beg for mercy.
Isn't that right, boys?
It's the best!
These guys are total scum!
As I suspected.
Well, in that case, do
you recognize these boots?
What are they supposed to be?
Hold on, boss.
Aren't those the boots we sold
for a pretty penny a while back?
That's right.
I stole them off of that hunter.
I remember now.
That chick was going on about
how she'd never hand them over
no matter what because she got
them from someone dear to her.
She was pissing me off, so
I cut off her freaking legs.
Oh, I see.
What a treat.
At last, I get to achieve my goal.
I've prayed for this moment countless
times, and now it's finally here.
You have no idea how
I've longed to find you.
You may beg me for forgiveness.
You may cry from the pain.
You may even attempt to repent,
but none of it will save you.
I'm not alone.
I'll see you soon.
This memory is the only one.
I'm going to go to the end of the world.
I'm going to move on
to the end of the day.
This memory is the only one.
I'm going to leave you
with the end of the world.
I'm going to go to
the end of the world.
You could even win a reward.
I look forward to serving you again.